## **Anton Tugaenko**

Software Engineer

#### I am

□ anton@tugaenko.com



Amsterdam, Netherlands

A software engineer specialized in Python, with 7 years of experience and a background in experimental physics. Teaching software engineering fundamentals to adult students as a part-time role. Going to start working at Uber in October 2024.

#### **Experience**

**Tutor (part-time)** @ Yandex.Practicum, mentors' team. Pursued as a hobby, yet remunerated December 2021 – November 2023



Yandex Practicum is an educational platform backed by the largest tech player in Russia.

- Empowered students to become market-fit backend developers, with over 50% securing employment
- Led a group of students with an outstanding survival rate (top 3 throughout the whole program)

Stack: Python, Django, SQLite, PostgreSQL, REST, NGINX, Docker, Github Actions, Yandex Cloud

# **Software Engineer** @ <u>Positive Technologies</u>, web application <u>firewall</u> backend team January 2021 – July 2022



Positive Technologies is an industry leader in cybersecurity and a major global provider of information security solutions.

- Developed features called 'user rules' and 'black/white lists'
- Sped up several slow parts up to 10 times by profiling, refactoring and query optimizing

Stack: Python, aiohttp, PostgreSQL, Rabbit MQ, gRPC, REST, NGINX, Kubernetes, git, Teamcity

### Software Engineer @ Yandex.Taxi, B2B backend team

July 2018 – January 2021



Yandex is the largest tech firm in Russia. Yandex.Taxi, online ride-sharing service, operates taxi aggregation and food tech businesses and was a business merged with <u>Uber</u> on several markets. The company is a global leader in self-driving technology.

- Collaborated closely with product managers on various business-related tasks
- Played a key role in the successful launch of <u>business-account</u> feature
- Streamlined customer connection processes by developing a simplified registration process, resulting in a tenfold reduction in required fields and significantly higher conversion rates

Stack: Python, aiohttp, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, REST, in-house equivalents of Kafka (Logbroker), MapReduce (YT) and AWS (Yandex Cloud)

#### **Software Engineer** @ <u>Iponweb</u>, core server team

**IPONWEB** 

October 2016 – July 2018

Global company specializing in real-time advertising platforms. Was recently acquired by Criteo – a global leader in Commerce Media.

- Designed Video Ad Serving Template library
- Refactored native ads library resulting in a 30% speed boost
- Led server-side Lua code overhaul to eliminate global scope pollution

Stack: Lua, Python, Perl, MongoDB, Mercurial, Jenkins

#### Self-Educator @ home

July 2016 - October 2016

Prepared myself for a career pivot through self-guided learning on platforms like Udacity and Coursera

## **Lead Engineer Physicist / Product Owner** @ Inkram (gas analyzers developer), R&D dept. February 2011 – June 2016



- Managed a team of engineers and workers. Supervised the development of complex technical devices
- Led several industry-related research projects and adapted prototypes for mass production, integrating my background in physics, electrical engineering, and embedded systems

Engineer Physicist @ MEPhI (Moscow Engineering Physics University), laser physics lab May 2005 – February 2011



- Scientific work. Research, papers, conferences and so on. Mentored students
- Played a key role in development of explosives gas analyzer based on <u>FAIMS</u> and laser ionization

### **Education and Scientific Work**

- PhD in Laser Physics | June 2010 | National Research Nuclear University "MEPhI"
- Masters in Solid State Physics | February 2006 | National Research Nuclear University "MEPhl"
- 5 patents and 15 scientific publications (all about physics and technology).
- 17 programming courses completed on Coursera, Udacity, etc. | 2015 2016

